Many of us were told from an early age that, be it at school or in life, "you learn from your mistakes".
我们很多人从小就被告知，无论是在学校还是生活中，“吃一堑，长一智”。
But is this actually true?
但这话真的成立吗？
The short answer is 'yes' – failure can be a teachable moment.
简短的答案是“是的”——失败可以成为一个具有教育意义的时刻。
But learning from our mistakes is, in reality, very hard because we don't like to fail.
但事实上，从错误中学习并非易事，因为我们都不喜欢失败。
It doesn't feel good, so we react to failure in impulsive and emotional ways, like giving up on a task prematurely, telling ourselves we don't care whether we succeed, or finding fault with the task itself.
失败的感觉并不好，所以我们会以冲动且情绪化的方式应对它，比如过早放弃一项任务、告诉自己不在乎成败，或是批评任务本身就有问题。
This is self-protective, according to Hallgeir Sjåstad, a professor of psychology and leadership at the Norwegian School of Economics.
挪威经济学院心理学与领导力教授哈尔盖尔·肖斯塔德表示，这种反应是一种自我保护。
"Most of us want to think of ourselves as competent and capable", he says, so when we fail "it poses a serious threat to our self-image".
他说：“我们大多数人都希望认为自己是有能力、能胜任的”，因此当我们失败时，“这会对我们的自我形象构成严重威胁”。
Fortunately, there is research to suggest that there are some strategies to help us overcome the emotional barriers around failure.
幸运的是，有研究表明，存在一些策略可以帮助我们克服围绕失败产生的情绪障碍。
One of them is to adopt a third-person perspective.
其中之一是采用第三人称视角。
Instead of asking "Why did I fail?", we could ask "Why did Sam fail?", for example.
比如，不要问“我为什么失败了？”，而是问“山姆为什么失败了？”。
Multiple studies by psychologist Ethan Kross at the University of Michigan show that adopting a third-person perspective helps to soften our negative emotional reactions, allowing us to look at failure more objectively.
密歇根大学心理学家伊桑·克罗斯开展的多项研究显示，采用第三人称视角有助于缓和我们的负面情绪反应，让我们能更客观地看待失败。
A second strategy involves offering advice to others who may be in the same position as us.
第二种策略是为那些可能和我们处于相同境遇的人提供建议。
This strategy led to better levels of motivation and academic success in the test groups – involving both adults and children – that were asked to give advice based on their own failures.
在一项涉及成人和儿童的测试中，那些被要求根据自己的失败经历给出建议的组别，展现出了更高的积极性和学业成就。
Professors Eskreis-Winkler, Fishbach and Duckworth found that the satisfaction of helping others "forces people to engage with their experience and what they have learned".
埃斯克雷斯-温克勒、菲什巴赫和达克沃斯三位教授发现，帮助他人带来的满足感“会促使人们反思自己的经历以及从中收获的教训”。
The writer Samuel Beckett once said: "fail again, fail better".
作家塞缪尔·贝克特曾说过：“再试一次，败得更漂亮些。”
But it now seems that we should be saying: "fail again, fail smarter".
但现在我们似乎应该说：“再试一次，败得更明智些。”
Failure is an inevitable part of life, but by learning to overcome the emotional barriers around it, we may find the road to success is a little easier to navigate.
失败是人生中不可避免的一部分，但通过学会克服其带来的情绪障碍，我们或许能让通往成功的道路变得更容易一些。